chevening.com 2009-06-16

# Privacy | Chevening.com

**The Fair Use Of Your Information**

The Foreign and Commonwealth Office (FCO) are the sole owners of the personal information collected from this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others. 

**Eligibility**

Scholars will have lifetime access to Chevening.com provided that they comply with the Terms and Conditions of the website and abide by the terms and conditions of their scholarship as laid down by the United Kingdom's Foreign and Commonwealth Office, the sponsors of the Chevening programme. If they are in default of any of these conditions, access to Chevening Online may be withdrawn. 

**Registration**

In order to become a member, users have to complete a registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). The site is password protected. 

**Links**

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that FCO/Chevening.com are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of these third party sites. 

**Surveys & Competitions**

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or competitions. Participation is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose any information requested. 

**Post Facility**

Members will be able to post questions, answers or commentary on our site. 

**Security**

This web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the web site, the information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration form asks users to enter personal information, that information is encrypted and is protected with SSL (Secure Socket Layer). While on a secure page, such as our registration form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, as will be the case for most of the time that a user is browsing the web. If you have any questions about the security at our web site, you can send an email to [chevening.online@britishcouncil.org](mailto:chevening.online@britishcouncil.org)

**Log Files**

We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order to improve the service to you. 

**Cookies**

The site uses cookies, small text files written to the user's hard drive, which contain the User ID. Cookies do not contain any personal information about the user. They are session cookies, employed to save the user time on Chevening Online and personalise a user's experience of the website, and disappear when the user logs out of the site. 

**Chevening Online Privacy Statement**

This website is owned and operated by The Foreign and Commonwealth Office, whose address is King Charles Street, Whitehall, London SW1A 2AH. All data provided by members of the Community is controlled by the Foreign and Commonwealth Office, King Charles Street, London W1A 2AH. 

Under the terms of the United Kingdom's Data Protection Act 1998, The Foreign and Commonwealth Office (FCO) are required by law to manage securely any personal information you give to us about yourself and only for the following purposes: 

  * To enable BC and FCO to maintain contact with you during the period of your scholarship and thereafter throughout you career 
  * To maintain educational and personal details of Chevening scholars 
  * To enable scholars to register for membership and participate in Chevening Online 
  * To be able to cater for any individual requirements you may have 
  * To enable us to customise the site according to individual selections 
  * To improve the services we offer 
  * To inform you of events and activities of relevance to your status as a current or former British Chevening scholar 
  * To run voluntary user surveys and competitions
  * To make you aware of our services and events (see below) 
  * To make you aware of services and events offered by third parties (see below) 

**Transferring your information overseas**

Using the Chevening website necessitates the transfer of your information to countries that may not have Data Protection legislation equivalent to that of the UK. 

**Disclosure**

Access to the personal details which you wish to be kept on the database will be granted only to : 

  * Designated staff of The British Council and FCO both in UK and in overseas Missions 
  * Organisations processing your information under our instructions 
  * Other members of Chevening Online via the website (those details which you have elected to be visible) 

**Your rights**

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as the institution, course etc), or if you no longer desire our service, we will correct, update or remove your personal data as provided to us. This can usually be done by you at the personal profile page or by sending an email to [chevening.online@britishcouncil.org](mailto:chevening.online@britishcouncil.org). 

You have the right to ask for a copy of all the information we hold on you, for which we will charge a fee. If you wish to see a copy contact the Data Protection Officer, The British Council, 10 Spring Gardens, London SW1A 2BN or [mailto://data.protection@britishcouncil.org](mailto:data.protection@britishcouncil.org).
